



Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Client Management, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Web Development, Project Management, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Java, Maven



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months Current Company: PayTM

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Client

Management, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Web Development, Project

Management, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Java, Maven

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Skilled Java developer and team leader with diverse experience utilizing Java tools for client-server environments and understanding of many programming languages including C, C++, and HTML. Worked with a medium size team of Java developers to maintain and improve company projects. Assisted with disaster recovery environments for critical business applications.

Work Experience

PayTM as Software Developer Jun 2018 to Till Date

Currently working on Equity Section.

We are building solution for all kind of investors (i.e. small, big) who can come to our platform and trade seamlessly.

My responsibility is to understand the system of other trading platforms like (Zerodha, reliancesmartmoney etc.) and design the solution to fit in Paytm System. Currently developing FMS (Fund management System) which help user to add/withdrawal money in trade account. After that he use money in trading. Already developed watch-list

functionality of users. Worked on REST services and cron .

Incture Technology as Software Developer Jul 2016 to Jun 2018

Handling java development including code & troubleshooting of applications.

Monitoring service based project progress & outstanding issues and ensuring the quality & timeliness of the deliverable preparing monthly dashboard, project health check metrics and weekly & fortnightly status reports as well as extending post-implementation support to team members by identifying defects, inconsistencies & errors.

Completing product development as per requirements, schedules & activities; contributing to team meetings, handling troubleshooting, and development & production problems across multiple environments/operating platforms.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Rajasthan University in 2012

PG: MCA (Computers) from National Institute of Technology (NIT), Hamirpur in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
JAVA,OS & DBMS	1.7	2019	1 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
SAP BPM	7.5	2018	1 Year(s)	
Java REST Service	1.1	2019	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
EJB Beans	3.0	2018	1 Year(s)	
spring boot	2	2019	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
JPA	2.1	2019	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Hibernate	5.2	2019	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert			
English	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Fund Management System Client: PAYTM MONEY LIMITED

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2020 - Till Date Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 4 Skill Used: Spring Boot, MySQL, Redis, Core Java, AWS-SQS,RestApi

Role Description: Writing Java Rest Services. Gathering Requirement from customer

Project Details: This is project is about handling user (trader/investor) money.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time